[
  {
    "question": "329. Hydroplaning can happen:",
    "choices": [
      "a. Only in heavy rainstorms.",
      "b. Only on rough road surfaces.",
      "c. If the thread is worn."
    ],
    "answer": "c. If the thread is worn."
  },
  {
    "question": "330. You are driving an 80-foot vehicle at 45 mph in good weather conditions. The least amount of space that you should keep in front of your vehicle to be safe is:",
    "choices": [
      "a. 9 seconds.",
      "b. 3 seconds.",
      "c. 5 seconds."
    ],
    "answer": "a. 9 seconds."
  },
  {
    "question": "331. Which of these statements about crossing traffic with a large vehicle is true?",
    "choices": [
      "a. Smaller vehicles need larger gaps in traffic than larger ones.",
      "b. Larger vehicles need larger gaps in traffic than smaller ones.",
      "c. Windshield washer antifreeze should be used."
    ],
    "answer": "b. Larger vehicles need larger gaps in traffic than smaller ones."
  },
  {
    "question": "332. Which of these statements about tires and very hot weather driving is true?",
    "choices": [
      "a. You should replace your tires every 10,000 miles in hot weather.",
      "b. You don't need to inspect your tires in hot weather.",
      "c. You should inspect your tires every two hours or 100 miles."
    ],
    "answer": "c. You should inspect your tires every two hours or 100 miles."
  },
  {
    "question": "333. Which of the following is a proper braking technique once the vehicle is in low gear?",
    "choices": [
      "a. Apply the brakes firmly to come to a complete stop.",
      "b. Keep the brakes applied continuously while in low gear.",
      "c. Apply the brakes enough to slow down approximately 5 mph below your safe speed, release the brakes; repeat the procedure when you reach your safe speed."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Apply the brakes enough to slow down approximately 5 mph below your safe speed, release the brakes; repeat the procedure when you reach your safe speed."
  },
  {
    "question": "334. A hazard ahead may cause your vehicle to collide with another if you do not take action. You should remember that:",
    "choices": [
      "a. You can always stop in time to avoid a collision.",
      "b. You can almost always turn more quickly than you can stop.",
      "c. You should never attempt to turn to avoid a collision."
    ],
    "answer": "b. You can almost always turn more quickly than you can stop."
  },
  {
    "question": "335. You are driving a bus, and it goes into a front wheel skid, the vehicle will:",
    "choices": [
      "a. Slide straight ahead even if you turn the wheel.",
      "b. Skid to the side of the road.",
      "c. Stop immediately when you apply the brakes."
    ],
    "answer": "a. Slide straight ahead even if you turn the wheel."
  },
  {
    "question": "336. Which of these should you NOT do when caring for an injured person at a collision scene?",
    "choices": [
      "a. Keep the person warm.",
      "b. Keep the person still and comfortable.",
      "c. Keep an injured person cool."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Keep an injured person cool."
  },
  {
    "question": "337. Inspect your cargo after you have cooled:",
    "choices": [
      "a. 100 miles.",
      "b. 50 miles, depending on the law in the state you are in.",
      "c. 25 miles or 50 miles, depending on the law in the state you are in, then again after 3 hours or after you have driven 150 miles, and after every stop for a break."
    ],
    "answer": "c. 25 miles or 50 miles, depending on the law in the state you are in, then again after 3 hours or after you have driven 150 miles, and after every stop for a break."
  },

    {
      "question": "338. Which of these statements about alcohol is true?",
      "choices": [
        "a. Only heavy drinkers are affected by alcohol.",
        "b. Everyone who drinks is affected by alcohol.",
        "c. Alcohol does not affect professional drivers."
      ],
      "answer": "b. Everyone who drinks is affected by alcohol."
    },
    {
      "question": "339. Where must the shipping papers be for a vehicle placarded for hazardous material?",
      "choices": [
        "a. On the driver's seat if the driver is out of the cab.",
        "b. In the glove compartment.",
        "c. Under the driver's seat."
      ],
      "answer": "a. On the driver's seat if the driver is out of the cab."
    },
    {
      "question": "340. The maximum weight rating specified by the manufactured for a single vehicle including its load is the ?",
      "choices": [
        "a. GVWR",
        "b. GVR",
        "c. GWR"
      ],
      "answer": "a. GVWR"
    },
    {
      "question": "341. Rules governing the loading and securing of cotton, jute, lumber products, and other specialized cargos are contained in:",
      "choices": [
        "a. Federal Motor Carrier Safety Regulations (FMCSRs).",
        "b. State regulations.",
        "c. Title 13, CCR."
      ],
      "answer": "c. Title 13, CCR."
    },
    {
      "question": "342. A load that extends to the left must have an amber light on the external left side if it extends:",
      "choices": [
        "a. 6 inches or more.",
        "b. 8 inches or more.",
        "c. One foot or more."
      ],
      "answer": "c. One foot or more."
    },
    {
      "question": "343. Commercial drivers must notify their employer of any out-of-state conviction:",
      "choices": [
        "a. Immediately upon conviction.",
        "b. Within 30 days of conviction.",
        "c. Within 90 days of conviction."
      ],
      "answer": "b. Within 30 days of conviction."
    },
    {
      "question": "344. What are the three types of vehicle inspections?",
      "choices": [
        "a. Pre-trip, post-trip, and en-route.",
        "b. Vehicle inspection, load inspection, and paperwork inspection.",
        "c. Pre-trip, post-trip, and en-route."
      ],
      "answer": "a. Pre-trip, post-trip, and en-route."
    },
    {
      "question": "345. The posted speed limit is 65 mph. A vehicle transporting explosives may legally drive no faster than ____ mph, weather conditions permitting.",
      "choices": [
        "a. 50.",
        "b. 55.",
        "c. 60."
      ],
      "answer": "b. 55."
    },
    {
      "question": "346. You are checking your tires during your pre-trip inspection. Which of these statements is true?",
      "choices": [
        "a. Dual tires should touch each other.",
        "b. Dual tires should not touch each other.",
        "c. It doesn't matter if dual tires touch each other."
      ],
      "answer": "b. Dual tires should not touch each other."
    },
      {
        "question": "347. Which of these statements about checking your suspension system is true?",
        "choices": [
          "a. 1/4 or more missing leaves in any leaf spring will put the vehicle out of service.",
          "b. A few missing leaves in any leaf spring are acceptable.",
          "c. Leaf spring condition is not important for vehicle safety."
        ],
        "answer": "a. 1/4 or more missing leaves in any leaf spring will put the vehicle out of service."
      },
      {
        "question": "348. Which of these statements about vehicle fires is true?",
        "choices": [
          "a. Use gasoline to extinguish a vehicle fire.",
          "b. The best way to extinguish a vehicle fire is to blow on it.",
          "c. Cool a burning tire with water."
        ],
        "answer": "c. Cool a burning tire with water."
      },
      {
        "question": "349. It is illegal to drive a commercial motor vehicle with a BAC this high, even though a BAC below the level does not mean it is safe to drive.",
        "choices": [
          "a. 0.02%",
          "b. 0.04%",
          "c. 0.08%"
        ],
        "answer": "b. 0.04%"
      },
      {
        "question": "350. Maximum axle weight is usually set by a _____ formula.",
        "choices": [
          "a. Height",
          "b. Bridge",
          "c. Weight"
        ],
        "answer": "b. Bridge"
      },
      {
        "question": "351. Which of these is true regarding brake shoes?",
        "choices": [
          "a. Brake shoes should be replaced only when they are completely worn out.",
          "b. Brake shoes should not be worn dangerously thin.",
          "c. Brake shoe thickness is not important for safe braking."
        ],
        "answer": "b. Brake shoes should not be worn dangerously thin."
      },
      {
        "question": "352. If the drive wheels have poor traction, retarders may cause:",
        "choices": [
          "a. Improved traction.",
          "b. Skidding.",
          "c. Better fuel efficiency."
        ],
        "answer": "b. Skidding."
      },
      {
        "question": "353. The key principle in balancing cargo weight is to keep the load:",
        "choices": [
          "a. Shifted to the front.",
          "b. Shifted to the rear.",
          "c. Centered."
        ],
        "answer": "c. Centered."
      },
      {
        "question": "354. The California Driver Handbook suggests that you limit the use of your horn why?",
        "choices": [
          "a. It may startle other drivers.",
          "b. Horns are ineffective and should not be used.",
          "c. Using your horn is mandatory in all situations."
        ],
        "answer": "a. It may startle other drivers."
      },
      {
        "question": "355. Measured from the road surface, the maximum legal height of any vehicle and load not needing a permit is:",
        "choices": [
          "a. 10 feet.",
          "b. 12 feet.",
          "c. 14 feet."
        ],
        "answer": "c. 14 feet."
      },
      {
        "question": "356. When no signs are posted on a three-lane highway, a school bus transporting pupils must drive in _____ lane, except when passing, turning, or leaving the highway.",
        "choices": [
          "a. Lane one.",
          "b. Lane two.",
          "c. Lane three."
        ],
        "answer": "c. Lane three."
      },
      
        {
          "question": "357. Unless your employer requires immediate notice, California law states that you have _____ days to notify your employer of a collision in the employer's vehicle.",
          "choices": [
            "a. 1",
            "b. 3",
            "c. 5"
          ],
          "answer": "c. 5"
        },
        {
          "question": "358. The vehicle's parking brake should be tested when the vehicle is:",
          "choices": [
            "a. Moving",
            "b. Parked on an incline",
            "c. Stop"
          ],
          "answer": "c. Stop"
        },
        {
          "question": "359. Retarders are used to:",
          "choices": [
            "a. Help slow the vehicle while driving and reduce brake wear.",
            "b. Keep you from skidding where the road is slippery.",
            "c. Both A and B."
          ],
          "answer": "c. Both A and B."
        },
        {
          "question": "360. If you are towing a vehicle with a load that blocks your view to the rear, you must have:",
          "choices": [
            "a. A left-hand rear view mirror.",
            "b. A right-hand rear view mirror.",
            "c. Both left and right-hand rear view mirrors."
          ],
          "answer": "c. Both left and right-hand rear view mirrors."
        },
        {
          "question": "361. Which of these statements about marking a stopped vehicle is true?",
          "choices": [
            "a. The rear reflective triangle should never be moved once placed.",
            "b. If a hill keeps drivers behind you from seeing the vehicle within 500 feet, the rear reflective triangle should be moved to give adequate warning.",
            "c. Reflective triangles are not required for marking a stopped vehicle."
          ],
          "answer": "b. If a hill keeps drivers behind you from seeing the vehicle within 500 feet, the rear reflective triangle should be moved to give adequate warning."
        },
        {
          "question": "362. If you must stop in the road, you should put your reflective triangles within _____ minutes:",
          "choices": [
            "a. 2",
            "b. 5",
            "c. 10"
          ],
          "answer": "c. 10"
        },
        {
          "question": "363. What should you do if the road you are driving becomes icy?",
          "choices": [
            "a. Speed up to maintain control.",
            "b. Stop driving, as you can install chains.",
            "c. Turn off the engine and coast until the road improves."
          ],
          "answer": "b. Stop driving, as you can install chains."
        },
        {
          "question": "364. Which of these statements about stopping distance and braking speed is true?",
          "choices": [
            "a. Dry roads have no effect on stopping distance.",
            "b. Wet roads can double stopping distance at any speed.",
            "c. Stopping distance is not affected by road conditions."
          ],
          "answer": "b. Wet roads can double stopping distance at any speed."
        },
        {
          "question": "365. The most important space around your vehicle is the space:",
          "choices": [
            "a. Behind the vehicle.",
            "b. To the sides of the vehicle.",
            "c. Ahead of the vehicle."
          ],
          "answer": "c. Ahead of the vehicle."
        },
        {
          "question": "366. You want to make a left turn and there are two left turn lanes. You will be turning into a street with two lanes in each direction. You should:",
          "choices": [
            "a. Use the left-hand left turn lane.",
            "b. Use the center left turn lane.",
            "c. Use the right-hand left turn lane."
          ],
          "answer": "c. Use the right-hand left turn lane."
        },
        
          {
            "question": "367. Water on the brakes can cause:",
            "choices": [
              "a. Stronger brakes.",
              "b. No effect on brakes.",
              "c. Weak brakes."
            ],
            "answer": "c. Weak brakes."
          },
          {
            "question": "368. The safest way to keep brakes from getting too hot while going downhill is to:",
            "choices": [
              "a. Use the braking effect of the engine to control speed.",
              "b. Apply the brakes continuously to maintain a slow speed.",
              "c. Downshift only if the engine starts to overheat."
            ],
            "answer": "a. Use the braking effect of the engine to control speed."
          },
          {
            "question": "369. Which of these statements about quick steering movements is true?",
            "choices": [
              "a. Quick steering movements are safe for all vehicles.",
              "b. Quick steering movements are only a concern for small vehicles.",
              "c. Top heavy vehicles may tip over more easily when making quick steering movements."
            ],
            "answer": "c. Top heavy vehicles may tip over more easily when making quick steering movements."
          },
          {
            "question": "370. Which of these is the most important thing to remember about emergency braking?",
            "choices": [
              "a. You can still steer the vehicle if the wheels are skidding.",
              "b. If the wheels are skidding, you cannot control the vehicle.",
              "c. Emergency braking should only be used in minor situations."
            ],
            "answer": "b. If the wheels are skidding, you cannot control the vehicle."
          },
          {
            "question": "371. A vehicle transporting hazardous materials must place signboards on _____ sides.",
            "choices": [
              "a. 2.",
              "b. 3.",
              "c. 4."
            ],
            "answer": "c. 4."
          },
          {
            "question": "372. If a vehicle is loaded with too much weight on the steering axle, what can happen?",
            "choices": [
              "a. Improved steering response.",
              "b. Easier steering control.",
              "c. Difficult (hard) steering and possible damage to the tires."
            ],
            "answer": "c. Difficult (hard) steering and possible damage to the tires."
          },
          {
            "question": "373. A second conviction for operating a commercial vehicle under the influence of alcohol will result in a:",
            "choices": [
              "a. 1-year driving sanction.",
              "b. 5-year driving sanction.",
              "c. Life-time driving sanction."
            ],
            "answer": "c. Life-time driving sanction."
          },
          {
            "question": "374. Drivers must have a peace officer's authorization to change from a permitted route when _____ transporting:",
            "choices": [
              "a. Extralegal loads.",
              "b. Regular cargo.",
              "c. Hazardous materials."
            ],
            "answer": "a. Extralegal loads."
          },
          {
            "question": "375. Which of these statements about checking your wheels and rims is true?",
            "choices": [
              "a. Rust around wheel fasteners means they are tight.",
              "b. Rust around wheel fasteners may mean they are loose.",
              "c. Wheel fasteners should be covered in grease to prevent rust."
            ],
            "answer": "b. Rust around wheel fasteners may mean they are loose."
          },
          {
            "question": "376. Before you drive a vehicle that has been released for service by the maintenance mechanic, you should:",
            "choices": [
              "a. Ignore the mechanic's report.",
              "b. Make sure the vehicle has been released for service by the maintenance mechanic.",
              "c. Check the vehicle's fluids and tires, but no need to worry about the mechanic's report."
            ],
            "answer": "b. Make sure the vehicle has been released for service by the maintenance mechanic."
          },
          
            {
              "question": "377. Commercial drivers should inspect their vehicle within the first _ miles and then:",
              "choices": [
                "a. 50 miles, 150 miles or 3 hours.",
                "b. 25 miles, 75 miles or 2 hours.",
                "c. 100 miles, 200 miles or 4 hours."
              ],
              "answer": "a. 50 miles, 150 miles or 3 hours."
            },
            {
              "question": "378. What are some things to do at an accident scene to prevent another accident?",
              "choices": [
                "a. Try to get your vehicle to the side of the road.",
                "b. If you're stopping to help, park away from the accident.",
                "c. Put on the flashers and set out reflective triangles.",
                "d. All of the above."
              ],
              "answer": "d. All of the above."
            },
            {
              "question": "379. You should test the stopping action of your service brakes by allowing the vehicle to:",
              "choices": [
                "a. Move forward at about 2 mph and applying the brake pedal firmly.",
                "b. Move forward at about 5 mph and applying the brake pedal firmly.",
                "c. Move forward at about 10 mph and applying the brake pedal firmly."
              ],
              "answer": "b. Move forward at about 5 mph and applying the brake pedal firmly."
            },
            {
              "question": "380. You are backing a large vehicle. You should:",
              "choices": [
                "a. Back in the direction that feels easiest.",
                "b. Back in the direction that is most convenient for you.",
                "c. Back in the direction that gives you the best vision."
              ],
              "answer": "c. Back in the direction that gives you the best vision."
            },
            {
              "question": "381. Using your mirrors correctly means that you:",
              "choices": [
                "a. Should never rely on them for information.",
                "b. Know there are no blind spots that your mirror cannot show you.",
                "c. Know there are blind spots that your mirror cannot show you."
              ],
              "answer": "c. Know there are blind spots that your mirror cannot show you."
            },
            {
              "question": "382. The service brakes of a bus must be capable of stopping from an initial speed of 20 mph within a maximum stopping distance of:",
              "choices": [
                "a. 20 feet.",
                "b. 40 feet.",
                "c. 60 feet."
              ],
              "answer": "b. 40 feet."
            },
            {
              "question": "383. Which of these statements about certain types of cargo is true?",
              "choices": [
                "a. Stable loads such as hanging meat or livestock require extra caution on curves.",
                "b. Unstable loads such as hanging meat or livestock require extra caution on curves.",
                "c. All types of cargo are equally stable on curves."
              ],
              "answer": "b. Unstable loads such as hanging meat or livestock require extra caution on curves."
            },
            {
              "question": "384. Vehicles traveling over 40 mph should allow an extra vehicle ahead of space between you and the:",
              "choices": [
                "a. 1 additional second, over 40 mph.",
                "b. 2 additional seconds, over 40 mph.",
                "c. 3 additional seconds, over 40 mph."
              ],
              "answer": "a. 1 additional second, over 40 mph."
            },
            {
              "question": "385. When you drive at night you should:",
              "choices": [
                "a. Adjust your speed so that you can stop within your sight distance.",
                "b. Drive at the same speed as during the day.",
                "c. Drive faster to reach your destination sooner."
              ],
              "answer": "a. Adjust your speed so that you can stop within your sight distance."
            }
                    
                
            

    ]
    
    

